Working Inventory of the Robert E. Marshak Papers, 1947-1990
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
- Box Floor, 1980 Blacksburg Workshop
  - Participant's list. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 8)
  - T. Goldman; Barger Discussion; Session IIA, 1A discussion. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 9)
  - Greenberg: papers. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 10)
  - R. Davis: Session IIA, 1.b (experimental). (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 11)
  - Huang: Session IIA, 3.b. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 12)
  - N. Chang: Session IB, 2.c (theory). (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 13)
  - W. Manciano: Session IB, 2.b (theory). (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 14)
  - Biedenharn (discussion): Session IID, 3.c. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 15)
  - V. Barger: Session IIA, 1.a. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 16)
  - T. Kamae: Session IC, 2.c (experimental). (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 17)
  - R. Mischke: Session IIA, 1.c (experimental). (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 18)
  - R. Peccei: Session ID, 2.e. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 19)
  - Raffi: experiment. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 20)
  - P. Rosen: Session 2B, 1.d. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 21)
  - L. Trueman: Session ID, 3.c. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 22)
  - Zee: Session IIC, 3.a. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 23)
  - F. Avignone: Session IA, 1.c. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 24)
  - Sat AM copies: Perl, Weinberg, Nambu, Ginsey, Veltman, Mohapatra. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 25)
  - Sudanshan (discussion): Session IIC, 3.a. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 26)
  - M. Beg: Session IID, 3.b. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 25)
  - Anderson: Session IC, 2.c (discussion). (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 26)
  - R. Shrock: Session IIA, 1.c (theoretical). (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 27)
  - Srednicki: Session IID, 3.b. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 28)
  - Tsao. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 29)
  - M. Turner: Session IIA, 1.b (theoretical). (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 30)
  - Turner: Session IC, 2.d. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 31)
  - H. Tye: Session ID, 3.b (theory). (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 32)
  - Wali: Session IIC, 3.a. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 33)
  - Scientific papers and notes. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 34)
  - C. S. Wu: Session IA, 1.a. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 35)
  - Yao: Session IIC, 3.a. (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 36)
  - Tasue: submission? (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 37)
  - G. Young: Session IC, 2.c (experiment). (Box-folder Floor-Envelope 38)
  - Scientific notes and paeprs used at the workshop. (Box-folder Floor-Envelopes 39 to 45)
  - Talks from the workshop. (Box-item Floor-Tapes 1-12)
- Box 100 - Books, Pamphlets, Bound Reports, etc.
  - Rotblat, J. Scientist in the Quest for Peace. Cambridge: MIT Press, 1972. (Box-item 100-1)
  - Congres International sur le Rayonnement Cosmique, 1953. (Box-item 100-2)
  - Fujii, A. The Relativistic Quantum Theory of Elementary Particle Interactions. Lectures given by P. T. Matthews, 1957. (Box-item 100-3)
  - Conferenza Internazionale sulle particelle elementari e XLI Congresso Nazionale die Fisica, 1955. (Box-item 100-4)
  - Proceedings of the First Anniversary Symposium. In honor of R. E. Marshak, January 14-16, 1963. (Box-item 100-5)
  - Klaw, Spencer. The New Brahmins Sc ietific Life in America. New York: William Morrow & Company, 1968. (Box-item 100-6)
  - Cheng, Ta-Pei and Ling-Fong Le. Gauge Theory of Elementary Particle Physics. (Box-item 100-7)
  - Marshak, R. E. Lectures on Weak Interaction. Matscience Report 10. Notes prepared by T. K. Radha and K. Raman. (Box-item 100-8)
  - International Conference on Mesona and Recently Discovered Particles. Padova-Venezia, 1957. (Box-item 100-9)
  - Columbia College Tomorrow. Special Report prepared by the Association of Alumni of Columbia College, 1969. (Box-item 100-10)
  - Proceedings of the Twenty-Fifth Pugwash Conference on Science and World Affairs. India, January 13-19, 1976. (Box-item 100-11)
  - International Conference on Theoretical Physics, Abstract Book, Section A. Kyoto and Tokyo, 1953. (Box-item 100-12)
  - Neutrino '72, Europhysics Conference. Volume II. Hungary, June 11-17, 1972. (Box-item 100-13)
  - Neutrino '72, Europhysics Conference. Volume I. Hungary, June 11-17, 1972. (Box-item 100-14)
- Miscellaneous Box
  - Yellow notepad. (Box-item Misc.-1)
  - Correspondence from Bookworm & Silverfish for appraisal of manuscript collection, 1990. (Box-item Misc.-2)
  - Letters from Robert Oppenheimer (1953), Albert Einstein (1953), Simon Sonkin (1941), Abdus Salam (1955). (Box-item Misc.-3)
  - Summary of REM Papers at Special Collections. (Box-item Misc.-4)
  - Negatives. (Box-item Misc.-5)
  - Copy of Rochester Conference article. (Box-folder Misc.-1)
  - 16 photographs. (Box-folder Misc.-2)
  - Robert E. Marshak Collection Inventory (1994?). (Box-folder Misc.-3)
  - Oral history transcript-Part I & II. (Box-folder Misc.-4)
- Oversize Folder (Folder 1)
  - Architects of Modern Physics poster: photograph on poster displays the "delegates to the fifth of the series of international congresses on physics." For each of the 29 scientists, there is also a description of their education and accomplishments.
  - Institue Interuniversitaire des Sciences Nucleaires: Robert E. Marshak..."The Charge Independence Hypethesis in Nuclear Physics," 1954.
  - Photograph of the International Institute of Physics and Chemistry, XVIII, 1982.
  - Photograph of the Instituts Internationaux de Physique et de Chimie Fondes par E. Solvay, 1967.
  - Folio of Cinquantenaire due Premier Conseil de Physique Solvay, 1911-1961.
  - Broadside: Italian Physical Society, International School of Physics...Summer Course to be held in Varenna, Lake Como, 1954.